# **CHRIS OLIVER**

40 N Kingshighway Blvd Apt 4A, St. Louis, MO 63108
<a href="mailto:chris@excid3.com">chris@excid3.com</a> | Phone: +12174080040
<a href="mailto:excid3.com">excid3.com</a> | github.com/excid3

#### SKILLS

Web development and user experience architect experienced in web technologies including Ruby on Rails, Django, HTML, CSS, XML, JSON, SQL, and Javascript to build and design interactive web applications. Proficient with Ruby, Python, version control including Git, Bazaar, Subversion, and Mercurial and the GTK and wxWidgets UI toolkits.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Rails Developer**

June 2012 - Present

Consultant - St. Louis, MO

- Building and maintaining projects for multiple clients, organizations, and businesses
- Responsible for software development, deployment, and server set up and maintenance

Co-Founder July 2013- Present

LaunchCode – launchcode.org – St. Louis, MO

 Built LaunchCode.org as well as interviewed and placed aspiring software developers in paid apprenticeships in software development positions with local St. Louis companies

### **Rails Developer**

**August 2011 – June 2012** 

The Able Few - St. Louis, MO

 Lead developer for many client projects with responsibilities including working with clients and designers directly to implement projects in Ruby on Rails

#### **Programmer Analyst**

June 2011 - August 2011

The Genome Institute – St. Louis, MO

 Worked with cancer researchers and software developers to document and dynamically generate documentation websites for the purpose of fund raising

#### Web Developer

July 2010 - May 2011

Zooniverse - Edwardsville, IL

 Working with developers both locally and remotely using Capistrano and Amazon web services (EC2 and S3) to deploy Ruby on Rails web applications.

## Founder & Lead Developer

May 2008 - June 2011

Keryx Project - keryxproject.org - Jacksonville, IL

- Designed and implemented a desktop software package for computers without internet access to download software for Ubuntu Linux using Python, wxWidgets, and GTK.
- Shipped and supported over 150,000 copies used in third world countries, governments, and other systems with poor internet connections.

#### **Summer of Code Software Engineer**

May 2009 - September 2009

Google, Inc. - WinLibre - Jacksonville, IL

- Accepted as one of 1000 students world-wide into Google Summer of Code.
- Designed and implemented a software package system for Windows using Python

# **PUBLICATIONS**

**Offline Package Installation.** Full Circle Magazine. December 2009: Issue 32. Pp. 14-16. fullcirclemagazine.org.

#### **EDUCATION**

Southern Illinois University – Edwardsville

May 2011